softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Sad Sun Shower
((ヨタ：デコ　デコ　デコ！
Forehead, forehead, forehead!
（サクラ）もう！
人が気にしてることを！
Geez! Don't make fun!
わぁ！
ゴッツンコ！
えっ？
Huh?
雪？
Snow?
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　雪がコン」
Kon kon kon. It's snowing, kon!
（シカマル）ヨタに
気に入られたみたいだな　お前。
Yota seems to like you.
（いの）おでこがね！
Your forehead, that is.
ピッタンコ！
あなた…　何なの！？
Perfect.
Listen, you... What is it?
♪♪「コン　コン　コン　コン　コン　コン」
Kon kon kon! Kon kon kon!
「コン　コン　コン」って…。
Kon kon kon?
あぁ…　せっかくお家から
くすねた花束渡そうとしたらね→
Geez...
I wanted to give him flowers
I put together from our shop,
サスケ君　プイッて
無視して行っちゃったんだよ。
but Sasuke just ignored me
and left.
フフフ…　悲しいな。
いのが　かわいそう。
So sad. Poor Ino. Poor Ino.
かわいそうにね　いの。
ヨタ…。
Yota...
優しいんだね　あげる。
You're nice,
so I'll give you one!
《いのちゃん　積極的なんだ。
Ino is so bold...
サスケ君に　そんなこと…》
to behave that way with Sasuke...
楽しいの？　サクラ。
Are you having fun, Sakura?
えっ？
サクラが楽しいとヨタも楽しい。
Huh?
If Sakura is having fun,
Yota is happy too.
サクラ　何が楽しいのよ。
Sakura... Happy about what?
あっ…　違うの　いのちゃん。
Oh... It's nothing, Ino.
キャハハハ　ハハハッ！
ムーッ！
（チョウジ）ヨタは　お天気屋だね。
Yota is so fickle.
悲しけりゃ雨が降る。
楽しけりゃ雪が降る　か…。
When he's sad, it rains...
When he's happy, it snows.
んっ？
Huh?
WEATHER FOR SALE
んっ？
（いの）あの花…。
Those flowers...
（シカマル）ヨタが？
Did Yota come...?
里に？
To the village...?!
（チョウジ）もうダメだよ　ヨタ。
お前は里には秘密なんだから。
You mustn't do that, Yota.
You're supposed to be
a secret from the village.
見つかったら大変なことに
なっちゃうんだよ。
If you're discovered,
there's gonna be trouble.
誰にも見られてないだろうな。
No one saw you, right?
うん　私
誰にも見られてない！
Yup, no one saw me.
ホントか？
Are you sure?
１人　変な子がいた。
誰！？
Just one... weird kid.
Who?!
みんなが　お昼ごはん食べてるとき
１人だけお外に出てて→
He was the only one
outside during lunch...
鉄棒に座ってたよ。
sitting on the metal pole.
鉄棒？　ナルトか？
Metal pole?
Was it Naruto?
う～ん　もしかして　あの子！
Could it be...
that boy?
あっ　いるいる！
いつも１人で　なんか怒ってる！
Oh, I know which one!
He's always alone
and looks angry.
そう？　私には　なんか
ニヤけた顔して見てくる。　変なヤツ。
Really? He sorta smiles at me.
He's weird.
アンタに気があんじゃないの？
えっ！？　やめて。
Maybe he likes you?
What?! Cut it out!
ナルトは　お前に気づいたか？
Did Naruto notice you?
たぶん…　知らない。
Probably...
I dunno.
あのね　ヨタ。
もう絶対　里に行っちゃダメだよ。
Listen, Yota.
Don't go into the village
ever again.
見つかったら　私たち→
If you're discovered,
we might have to part ways.
離れ離れになっちゃうかも
しれないんだよ？
私　やだよ！
サクラと離れたくないよ！
I don't want that!
I don't want to be apart from Sakura!
サクラだけなの？
ありがとう　ヨタ。
Just Sakura?
Thank you, Yota.
でも　おもしろかったね　サスケ君。
Wasn't that funny though?
Sasuke who always acts so cool...
(いつも　クールなのに…
フフフッ　お花畑みたいだった))
looked like a flower garden.
くっ…。
やっぱり　ヨタと
戦うことになっちゃうの？
So does this mean
we have to fight Yota?
アスマのときのように
封印するため…。
It's like the time with Asuma.
In order to seal him...
うっ…　戦うしか…。
we have to fight!
でも　どうやって…
ヨタのお天気に　僕たち勝てるの？
But how?
Can we beat Yota's weather?
知るかよ！
How would I know?
（みんな）うわ～っ！
《考えてみたら
俺たち　なんにも→
Come to think of it...
We don't know anything about Yota.
ヨタのこと知らねえんだ。
どうやったら…》
How can we...?
《父さん　サクラにつなげて！》
Dad!
Connect me with Sakura!
（いのいち）わかった。
Huh?!
All right...
サクラ！
Sakura!
《いの：サクラ…　聞こえる？》
Sakura, can you hear me?!
《いの…　ごめん。
ちょっと取り込んでる》
Ino?!
Sorry, I'm in the middle
of something right now!
《アンタ　覚えてない？
Do you remember?
覚えてるでしょ？　ヨタのこと！》
You must!
About Yota!
《ちょ…　ちょっと待って。
今　そのヨタが目の前に…》
Wait, I'm...
facing that Yota right now!
どういうこと？
What's going on?!
《キバ：俺んところもだよ！
Over here too!
キバ：ヨタのヤツ　すんげぇ怒ってる》
Yota's really mad.
なに！？
What?!
《て　なんで　お前たちんとこにも
ヨタがいるんだよ？》
How come Yota's by you guys too?
《ヨタが…　３人も》
Three Yotas?
いったい　どうなってる？
What's going on?
（ナルト）口笛…。
Whistling?
お前…　誰だ？
Who are... you?
なんだ？
What's this?
え…　あっ…。
Huh?
Hey...
なんか…。
Hold on!
お前　ヨタ？
You're... Yota?
ハハッ！
ヨタなのか？
Are you Yota?
ヨタ！！
Yota!
ナルト？
Naruto...
ヨタ…。
Yota...
Huh?
((なんだよ？
What?
ちょっと　アンタね　ヨタをどこに…。
Hey, where'd you put Yota?
探り探りで聞くのは難しいな…
ナルト　お前　知ってるよな？
Interrogating him won't do.
Naruto, you know, right?
何を？
Know what?
う～ん…　何か見ただろ？
Well... You saw something, right?
見かけねえような…　その…。
You didn't see him? That...
見かけねえのを
どうやって見るんだよ？
If I didn't see him,
how could I have seen him?
お前　意外と頭いいな。
うん　うん。
Huh?
You're pretty shrewd, aren't you?
ちょっと　アンタたち
なに感心してんのよ。
Why are you guys so impressed?!
ちょっと…　来て！
ちょっ…　何？
Come with me!
Hey, what is it?
あ…。
ヨタを　どこへやったのよ！？
Where did you put Yota?!
え…　ヨタ？
Huh? Yota?
（サクラ）この前
アカデミーの校庭で会ったんでしょ？
You met him in the Academy schoolyard
the other day, didn't you?
ヨタを知ってるのは　私たちの他は
あなただけなんだから！
The only one who knows Yota
besides us is you!
アンタ！　ヨタに会ったんでしょ？
You met Yota, didn't you?
みんなに
ばらしちゃったんでしょ！？
You told everyone, didn't you?!
ヨタって　誰なんだよ？
Who's Yota?
里の近くで迷子になってたのよ。
He was a lost kid near the village.
かわいそうだから
私たちが面倒をみてさ…。
We felt sorry for him,
so we took care of him.
それが　今日　ここに来てみたら
めちゃくちゃで→
But when we came here today,
everything was a mess
and Yota was gone!
ヨタも　いないんだもん！
じゃあ　ソイツってば
よそ者じゃねえかよ。
Then he's an outsider?
えっ？
Oh...
なんで　よそ者のヤツは　かばって…
俺には　そんな目をしやがんだよ！
Why would you protect an outsider,
but still look at me
with those eyes?!
ちょっと…　何よ！？　その言い方！
Hey! What a thing to say!
生意気ね！
う～ん…。
He's so cocky.
って…　証拠も何もねえのに
問い詰めすぎたかな。
Maybe we questioned him too hard
when we don't even have proof...
もし　本当に
何も知らなかったら…。
If he really doesn't know anything...
チクショウ！
なんで　いつも　俺ばっか…。
Damn it!
Why is it always me?
迷った…。
I'm lost...
(お前…))
You...
((あっ！　もしかして…。
Are you...
ゲッ！　な…　なんなんだよ！？　お前。
どうしたんだってばよ？
Hey, hey!
What is it? What's wrong?!
どうしたんだよ？
What's the matter?
私…　怖いよ。
I'm scared.
私って…　何？
What's your name?
私は　ヨタだよ！
I'm Yota!
えっ！？　やっぱ　お前がヨタか！
Huh?!
So you're Yota, after all!
うわ～ん！
ギャーッ！　痛い　痛い…。
お天気雨？
Sun showers?
これって　もしかして　お前の術？
Is this... your jutsu?
いいな…　俺なんか　分身の術も
変化の術もできなくって→
Wow...
Like I can't even do Clone Jutsu
or Transformation Jutsu
いつも　イルカティーチャーに
怒られてばっかで…。
and Iruka Sensei is
always scolding me.
よそ者のくせに
みんなに好かれてよ。
You're an outsider,
but everyone likes you...
俺ってば…。
あ！
Yet when it comes to me...
Huh?!
私　知ってるよ　お前。
I know you!
フーッ　フーッ　フーッて。
You were doing... fuu fuu fuu.
ん？
この前　鉄棒に座って→
Huh?
You were sitting on the metal pole
the other day and whistling.
口で笛吹いてた。
あ…。
Oh...
教えて　私も口で笛吹きたい。
Teach me how.
I want to whistle too.
は？
だって　アンタ笛吹いたら→
Huh?
When you whistled,
you weren't alone...
１人じゃなくなってた。
元気出てた。
You cheered up.
出てねえよ。　口笛で
ごまかしてただけだってばよ。
I wasn't.
I was pretending... by whistling.
じゃあ　ヨタもごまかしてみる。
Then I'll try pretending too.
だって　お前には　みんながいて…。
Look, you have everyone...
お前…。
You...
教えておくれよ　私にも口笛。
Please teach me...
how to whistle.
ああ。
Sure...
見てろよ　ここ。
Watch me...
はじめは
とんがらせないで息を出すんだ。
First, you just blow
without pursing your lips.
で　だんだん狭くする。
Then slowly pucker up.
風の音を出すんだ　ひゅ～って。
Make wind sounds... Like "fuuu"!
うん。
《コイツ　喜んでやがる。
He's... happy.
喜びが風になるのか》
So his happiness turns into wind.
ねぇ。
Say...
なに？
What is it?
友達。
Fr-i-e-nd.
友達だってばよ！
You're my friend!
（２人）アハハハッ。
（キバ）あ　いやがった　この野郎！
Hey, there he is! That kid!
待て　コラ！
Hey wait!
ヤダ！
No!
コイツ　また。
ヨタ！
That brat, not again!
Yota!
私　犬嫌い！
I don't like dogs!
お前ら　ヨタに何したんだよ！
What did you do to Yota,
you guys?!
知らねえよ。　赤丸と
散歩してたら　ヤツに会って…。
I don't know!
I was walking Akamaru...
and I saw him.
したら　雷が　バンバン落ちてきて。
Then thunder started
rumbling everywhere.
コイツの仕業だろ！
It's his doing, right?
うわ～っ！
ヨタ！
あっ　あの子！
Yota!
Oh, it's him!
キャー！
ヨタ…。
Yota...!
プン　プン　プン。
ヨタのヤツ　怒ると雷かよ。
When Yota gets mad,
he makes thunder?!
それ！
Go!
（みんな）わ～！
よしよし。
There, there...
い～ち　に～　さ～ん→
One, two...
three, four...
し～　ご～　ろ～く　な～な→
five, six...
seven, eight...
は～ち　きゅ～う　とお。
nine, ten, eleven, twelve...
じゅ～いち　じゅ～に→
じゅ～さん　じゅ～し…。
thirteen, fourteen, fifteen...
私もナルトと一緒！
バカ　ヨタ！
I'm with you, Naruto.
Don't be silly, Yota.
お前がいると　すぐわかっちまう。
If you stay with me,
he'll find me right away.
キュフフフ。
バカッ　バカ！
Hey, stop it!
Don't act so happy.
そうやって　嬉しそうにしちゃ
ダメだって！
お前が天気変えちまうから
ばれるんだよ！
The weather will change
and he'll know where we are!
ナルトが怒った。
Naruto's mad...
もぉ～　バカヨタ！
あっちいけ　あっち。
Oh no! Stupid Yota!
Go away! Shoo!
（キバ）きゅうじゅうはち
きゅうじゅうきゅう→
Ninety-eight, ninety-nine...
ひゃ～く！
One hundred!
ナルトみっけ！
くっそ～　ヨタめ。
Found you, Naruto.
Damn it! That Yota...
俺を助けるために
缶を蹴ってくれるヤツなんて→
Is there someone who'll kick
the can to save me?
いるのかな？
うっ　おわっ…。
シカマル　チョウジ　いの　赤丸　で　サクラ！
Shikamaru, Choji, Ino,
Akamaru and Sakura!
あとは　ヨタか。
Yota's the only one left.
ヨタ…。
Yota...
ヨタ？
Yota?
ヨタが泣いてる！
Yota is crying...
ヨタ！
Yota!
はっ！
ヨタ！
Yota!
あの者は　我らが預かる。
We are taking him into custody.
厳重な監視のもと
取り調べを行う。
He will be kept under strict
observation and interrogated.
ちょっと！　ヨタは　そんなんじゃ…。
But Yota isn't like that...!
木ノ葉の里以外の者が→
Other than members of the Hidden Leaf,
許可なく里周辺に
存在することは　許されない。
no one is allowed around the village
borders without authorization.
いずれ
キミたちにも出頭してもらう。
You will also be summoned
in time.
それまで
自宅で待機しているように。
Until then, go back home
and remain there.
(ヨタは　ヨタは　俺の…))
Yota... Yota is my...
《あれが　俺たちとヨタとの
別れの始まりだった》
That was the start of
our parting with Yota.
《そして
俺たちは　ヨタを死なせた》
And we allowed...
Yota to die...
I was tired of walking and didn't know what I should do
aruki tsukarete tohou ni kureta
my teacher told me to go towards a bright future
akarui mirai e sensei wa iu kedo
but which way should I go to find the light?
docchi ni aruitara hikari wa sasu kana
I have no idea at the moment so let's go
toriaezu wakaranai kedo ikouze
don't tell me things I want to hear
kirei goto nanka maji kan kanben desu
just give me something so powerful that it hurts
itai kurai tsuyoi yatsu wo choudai
I'm rebelling against the ordinary life
arikitari na mainichi ni hankou desu
burning up the mic with our rock
tagire m i c oretachi no rock
I can hear you are screaming
kimino koe ga kikoeru
that's the only thing that's real, let it explode
sore dake wa real sa hajikero
this song
kono uta
i can hear you are screaming
I'm running through the night on impulse
tsuki ugokasare shoudou no mama ni yoru wo kakenda
can't you see can't you see can't you see my face
I want to sense this moment not just the words, I want to sense you
kotoba ja nai ima dake wo kanjitetai kimi wo kanjitetai
i can hear you are screaming
keep on shouting and open the door to tomorrow
sakebi tsuzukete ashita no tobira wo kojihirakerunda
don't worry don't worry don't worry baby
I want to believe in us, not anyone else, I want to believe in my dream
dareka ja nai oretachi wo shinjitetai yume wo shinjitetai
Get a grip, Yota! It's all right now!
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
It's time for me to go.
What are you talking about?
From now on, we're...
I'll never forget about you guys.
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のあれよ
But you guys will forget about me.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Lingering Snow"
＜　その魚とは…＞
There's no way
I could forget you!
＜　それは鰹に勝るとも劣らない
味を持つことから→